# **KASHISH KHARBANDA**

A self-driven digital native carrying a high level of enthusiasm for Information Technology and Entrepreneurship. Well-versed with Computer Science and Data Science principles. 4 years of tutoring experience in the CS landscape, 3 years of experience interning in the industry, 2 years of experience in leadership roles. Growth minded with a vision of creating an impact. A people person looking for opportunities that leverage strong leadership and collaborative skills!

# Contact

🟠 Greater Seattle Area



(404) 518-0072



🔽 kashishkhar@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/kashishk/



🔗 <u>kashishkhar.github.io/profile/</u>

# Skills

### **Professional**

Leadership Willingness to learn Adaptability Dependability Time Management

**Technical** Java Python Pandas, Numpy, MatPlotLib Technology Blogging SQL, PostrgeSQL Git Cloud, Data Migration MS Office

# Education

### University of California, Berkeley Aug 2019 - May 2023

Computer Science, Data Science Certificate of Entrepreneurship&Tech

#### Relevant coursework:

- Structure/Interpretation of Computer **Programs**
- Data Structures
- Foundations of Data Science
- Principles/Techniques of Data
- Designing Information Devices and Systems (I & II)
- Introduction to Entrepreneurship

## North Creek High School

Sep 2017 - June 2019

High School Diploma

**Organizations:** Future Business Leaders of America, Technology Student Association, HOSA, Girls Who Code, National Honor Society, American Cancer Society

# **Experience**

### **Summer Extern**

Jun 2020-Aug 2020

Certified for 80 hours of IT, Business, and Professional Development training.

### Al Platform Intern

#### **Microsoft Corporation**

June 2019-August 2019

Used Python and SQL to understand the unexpected change of data features overtime and learned how to address the resulting model accuracy degradation.

### Data Science Intern

### **Microsoft Corporation**

Jun 2018-Aug 2018

Worked on Data Migration and SKU Recommendation to predict the best Azure SQL Database SKU for an on-premises database; used Python, C#, SQL, U-SQL in Azure Data Lake, and PostgreSQL.

# Extracurriculars

### Data Science Research Mentor

**Undergrad Laboratory @ Berkeley** 

Sep 2020-present

Research mentor in Data Science division; responsible for leading and mentoring 4-5 students for research project being presented in May 2021.

### External Events & Partnerships

#### Opportunity Through Data

Sep 2020-present

Part of strategic operations team with the vision of improving access to Data Science education, particularly in underrepresented communities.

### **Committee Member**

#### FEMTech @ Berkelev

Sep 2019-present

2019 | Managed financial sector of club (budgeting, reimbursements). 2020 | Hosting career-related events for females in Technology/STEM.

### Founder & President

#### FBLA @ North Creek High School

Sep 2017-Jul 2018

Founded school's FBLA chapter by establishing the chapter's authenticity and legacy. Led more than 100 members as President.

# **Projects**

### **Stock Market Prediction**

In Progress

As part of UC Berkeley's Data Science Society, used a 64-feature Open High Low Close stock market dataset for 10 NASDAQ-100 companies to extract the technical indicators needed to predict stock market trends.

#### **Facial Detection**

June 2020

Learned about Computer Vision and utilized Machine Learning based Haar Cascade classifiers with Adaboost to identify objects in images and videos, particularly human facial features.

## **Inclusive Meeting**

Used Natural Language Processing to perform sentimental analysis on team meeting conversations and gauge certain factors such as tone of speaker, productivity of meeting, etc. Also learned about data privacy.

# **Activities and Awards**

- **Juni Learning** | CS instructor for Python, Java, and AP CS [present]
- Google NCWIT | Award recipient
- Mobile Application Development | Top 15 at FBLA Nationals
- Relay for Life cancer nonprofit | Team captain, Social Media Lead
- Girls Who Code | Volunteer and Tutor